[theme song playing]
[Polly] Welcome to the opening
of the Grace Shelby Institute
for the non-insured children of the poor.
I would very much like you to join me
in thanking the man that made the founding
of this establishment actually possible.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. Thomas Shelby.
[crowd applauding]
[Arthur] Speech!
Come on, speech!
[baby crying]
Say it, Tom. Say it to 'em!
[John] Lay the foundation!
[indistinct chatter]
Um, I didn't come here today
to make a speech, but I will say this.
These children are now safe.
In our care, they will be safe.
Because we are from the same cold streets
as they are.
And in our care,
they won't be shipped away
to the colonies.
Or separated from kin.
Or made to work for men
in their various ways.
They will grow up here. At home.
Loved.
In Birmingham.
Because this is our city.
By order of the Peaky Blinders.
Get up!
[crowd applauding]
Now, let us sing "Immortal Invisible."
[music playing]
[crowd singing hymns in distance]
You hear that, Grace?
[door opens]
The absence of my invitation
for this event
was obviously an oversight
on your part, Mr. Shelby.
But, look. I have the keys.
I've allocated myself an office.
Just there, two doors in from the street.
It's the one that already has the stove
and the crucifixion on the window.
Mr. Shelby?
It is the one that has the crucifixion
on the window in orange and red.
That will be my office.
And I will take them to Saint Aloysius
for confession.
You do understand
these keys are part
of our broader arrangement?
In the next 24 hours,
you will do exactly
as you have been instructed.
You'll not deviate. You'll not fail.
Come on, little fellas.
-Slow down. Slow down.
-[children speak indistinctly]
[children laughing]
The, uh…
The Lord Mayor would like you
to come and eat cake and drink some tea.
[sighs]
[Ada] Tommy says mingle and smile.
[door closes]
It must be the trains.
No Ruben?
Do you know any other guests from London
not turned up?
Some, I think, yeah.
Pol, I'm paid by the company now.
So I have to talk to other people.
So, you have moved from horses
to automobiles in just four years.
When you ship to New York,
you pay a higher dock duty.
You should consider coming with us
through Boston.
I just spoke to Johnny Dogs.
He said the tunnel's hit heavy clay.
-It's slowing him down.
-How long?
Two days before they hit the wall.
Tell him to dig a sink hole
to drain the clay.
He asked if you could go down
and have a look yourself.
I told him wild horses
wouldn't get you down.
-Mmm.
-[Tommy sighs]
Mr. Shelby, I would just like to say
that I wish I had met your dear wife
before she was taken from us,
and I would like to allocate an hour a day
of each of my ladies' time
to make winter clothes
for the little ones.
Speak to my secretary, Miss Stark,
in the gray hat.
She knows my diary.
Fuck me, Tom.
I don't know how you do it. Incoming.
-Mr. Shelby.
-Yes?
Oh, your little boy
looks so much like you.
Yes. Yes. He's a little rascal, isn't he?
Mr. Shelby, would it be too inconvenient
to steal you for a moment?
No, no. No inconvenience at all.
-Tommy, I'm sorry. He wants you.
-[baby crying]
-Oh, come here, Charlie.
-Here's Daddy.
Oh, little boy.
-[shushing]
-So lovely to see a man
willing to hold his child in public.
From the members of
Moseley War Widow's Institute.
What's this? What's this?
Made by Mr. Winslow himself
of Winslow's Castings.
Look at that.
From a photograph of your horse
that ran at the Derby.
Oh, that is very kind.
Thank you very much.
-Grace's Secret.
-Thank you very much.
-Look, Charlie.
-[crying]
Would you mind holding it for us so that
we can have a photograph for the gazette?
Hey. Hey. Hey.
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
-Thank you, Mr. Shelby.
-Not at all.
-[man] Look this way.
-Thank you.
-[shutter clicks]
-[women chuckling]
Thank you for your time, ladies.
Thank you.
Thank you for your time. Thank you.
[indistinct chatter]
-Where's Charles, Ada?
-I gave him to you.
-Where is he?
-I don't know.
Boys.
-Have you seen Charlie?
-[Arthur] Eh…
I don't know. He is playing, ain't he?
Pol, where's Charles?
-Lizzie. Where is Charlie?
-I don't know.
Where is he?
Back door. Kitchen.
Get to Blake Street where the cars are.
Tommy. Someone said they saw a nurse
take him through the back door.
-Fuck.
-What nurse?
I don't know. Go.
[rattling door knob]
[grunting]
-Arthur.
-What?
Somebody saw a woman
and a kid getting into a car.
Ah, fuck!
Charlie!
[retching]
John.
-Where is he?
-[Arthur] John!
-Arthur. Arthur, where is he?
-Go find Moss!
-Junctions, block them all off.
-Where is he?
-Tell me.
-Someone took him.
Listen to me.
They put him in a car.
They put him in a car and drove south.
We've got road blocks, we've got spotters.
I'll set up shop
-and put every man we've got…
-Yeah.
…between here and Maypole.
-Right. You do that.
-You gotta go to the office.
-Yeah.
-You gotta sit by the phone.
-You do that.
-Whoever took him is going to call.
Polly!
Let's go, Pol.
Stay by that phone.
Me and John will cover the roads.
I need Michael at the Maypole junction.
We need Moss to block all the roads south.
Give me Moss.
Gone where?
[telephone dings]
-[grunts]
-[clatters]
-Tommy…
-It's them.
-Who?
-It's fucking them.
Look. It might be some random woman.
-You know, sometimes women go mad…
-No, it's them.
-[thunder rumbling]
-Did you break the phone?
-You broke the phone.
-[door opens]
It's all right, we got another phone.
-[Ada] Tommy?
-Ada?
There's someone outside. A priest.
Stay here, Pol. Stay here.
Don't do anything.
[door opens]
[thunder rumbling]
We have your son.
Get in the car.
First.
Is he safe?
Of course, he's safe.
All children are dear to me.
You have all the cards.
Tell me what you want me to do
and I will certainly do it.
You ever drive one of these beasts?
I am asking you to conduct business.
I borrowed it.
Lent it. By a Lord.
For the duration of this business.
I will certainly do what you need me to do
with no complaints.
We were forced into doing
this awful thing.
We did warn you that your son would be
in danger if you deviated from the plan.
You made a mistake.
-You understand that?
-Yes.
What mistake did you make?
Do you even know?
Tell me what you want me to do.
You made a deal with our enemies.
I will do what needs to be done.
You went behind our backs to stop
the Soviets from blowing up the train.
But it's all right. It's all right.
We've rectified your mistake.
You ask me, "What do I need to do?"
Well, here is what you need to do,
you fucking mongrel, you.
But since the Bolsheviks
will not be blowing up the train,
you'll blow up the train yourself.
It's always been about the explosion.
From the beginning. The bang. The outrage.
Understand?
Those are notes and fragments for you
to scatter in the wreckage,
implicating named officials
from the Soviet embassy.
-I will scatter them. It will be done.
-Good.
Our friends at The Times
and the Daily Mail will do the rest.
And once the British Government
cuts diplomatic relations
with the Soviet Union,
that will be our mission accomplished.
You'll have been part of a fine adventure.
To help with the outrage,
we need people to die in the explosion.
How many?
Let's say… six.
Rail workers, perhaps.
Men from the factory.
And I want my son returned to me
within an hour of the explosion.
Oh, it's conditions now, is it?
We need to fix the handover in advance.
I haven't finished with you yet,
Mr. Shelby.
We also hear that you're digging a tunnel.
Mining for precious stones
under Wilderness House.
I'm told they have a Fabergé
in the strong room.
The Lilies of the Valley egg made in 1898.
One of the Odd Fellows has a wife
who is obsessed with Fabergé.
He wants to give it for her birthday…
He will have it.
And the Economic League will take
all of the jewels that you steal,
to cover our considerable expenses.
The fight against communism
is not cheap, you know?
-So, if you want to see your…
-I will give you all the jewels.
A bang first.
Then bring everything you've stolen
to your office at dawn.
No. No.
I'll not be able to get the jewels
to you by dawn.
The tunnel has hit clay.
If the St. Andrew's clock strikes
5:00 a.m. on the night of the robbery
and we don't have
everything that we asked for,
the bell will be tolling for your boy.
[thunder rumbling]
Now, get out of my fucking car.
[exhales]
-[Tommy] Where's Linda?
-With Esme.
Esme's waters broke.
I was just with her.
Running around fucking broke the waters.
Where's Finn?
Out with the young'uns
looking for the Riley.
We couldn't reach him.
I need to know who spoke.
Our enemies know everything. Everything.
I need to know who spoke
about business outside of the family.
and who they spoke to. Now.
-Tommy…
-Your wife, Arthur?
I'm gonna tell myself
that you're not thinking straight.
Your mind's not clear.
Or Esme getting cash
for cocaine, eh, John?
Fuck!
All of a sudden,
back in the family, Ada, eh.
That's a surprise. Out of the blue.
On whose orders?
Tommy, this is not helping find him.
And you and your painter.
You said he knows you.
Things developed. You talked.
If anyone has talked
about the tunnel to anyone else,
I need to know,
and I need to know this second.
-What about your clay kickers?
-[Arthur] Mmm.
Drunk in a pub.
I trust those men with my life.
More than you trust us?
Yeah.
As of an hour ago, yes.
[John] Where's Michael
in this lineup anyway?
-[Polly] Leave Michael out.
-Yeah?
-He should be here.
-I don't even know him.
How long you known him?
Fucking three years?
[Polly] He's not your whipping boy.
I don't even fucking know the boy.
I never told Michael
about the Lilies of the Valley.
The only people I told
about the Fabergé eggs are in this room.
Tommy, I want you to know
that I came back for love.
And common sense.
And Esme's got no need for extra cash.
[door opens and closes]
You bring my wife into this.
Means we speak when this business is done.
John, Arthur,
I need 50 sticks of BSA dynamite,
300 yards of cable
and six detonators by midday tomorrow.
This is evidence.
I need you to scatter it.
We're blowing up a train
and people are gonna die.
[door opens and closes]
Ruben and I talked about many things.
-But not that. Not ever.
-[door opens and closes]
Tommy. I'm sorry I'm late.
We looked everywhere.
All the way up to Hay Mills.
So, nothing.
Put four cans of petrol
in the boot of my car and bring it around.
And put cigarettes and a lamp in the box.
Fetch Michael. I need him.
Ada told me he gave you red wine.
I imagine you can't remember
half of what you talked about.
He was never interested in business.
He came to you at my wedding.
He pursued you. Sought you out.
Why would an educated man of his standing
do something like that?
You mean, to a woman like me?
Yes.
I've done the odds on all of you.
Evens it's him.
There's another possibility.
But evens it's him.
[door opens and slams shut]
[Polly sniffling]
[Polly sobbing]
[screams]
[Alfie grunts]
I asked you to come alone and unarmed.
Yeah, well, alone I ain't never gonna do,
am I?
And as for the cane, don't worry about it.
That is just my sciatica.
It always plays up around the winter
and the summer solstice.
What have you got for me, Alfie?
What did you bring me here for?
It's on the way to somewhere
I need to be in a hurry.
-Huh.
-What have you got for me?
Well, seeing as you was prepared
to pay such an exorbitant amount
for this information,
I decided to give you value for money.
So, here are the names
of all the men in England
whom I would approach, right,
if I had a Fabergé egg for sale.
There you go.
And then, here's all the men
on that list, you know,
who would buy the old Fabergé egg
even if they knew
that that item was stolen, eh.
Then in come your curious
fucking gyppo question.
I won't ask, but, um…
Here is a list of the men
who would buy a Fabergé
because of their wife's obsession.
Oh, yes. Thank you, Mr. Shelby.
Lovely doing business with you.
[gun clicks]
You left a name off the list, Alfie.
-Did I?
-Yeah.
I've already spoken to my people
in the jewelry quarter,
experienced dealers.
They tell me there are only three men
in Britain
whose wives are obsessed with Fabergé.
Makes them good customers.
You missed the richest one off the list.
Yeah, well, if you knew already,
how come you dragged me all the way
out into the fucking oggin, mate?
Two reasons. Reason one,
by withholding a name
that you most certainly know,
you've proven you have done a deal
with the Odd Fellows.
It was you who told them about the tunnel.
You who told them
about the fucking deal with the Soviets.
Reason two,
the name of the man
that you are withholding must be my enemy
otherwise you wouldn't be protecting him.
He's now a man I can use.
Listen, sweetie, you can't take a man--
You gave information
in exchange for a share.
Tommy, there were things in that treasury
that God himself, he spoke to me.
He said, "Alfie, you are meant
to have these things."
You crossed the line, Alfie.
-You fucking what?
-You crossed the line.
-The line?
-They're using my boy!
Did you fucking know?
Yeah, I knew, you know.
But damned as I am,
it made no fucking difference to me mate.
[grunting]
[Alfie choking]
Fucking hell, Tommy.
[gun clicks]
[Alfie] Oh, for crying out loud.
What the fuck is going on?
What is the matter with you,
Tommy, eh? Eh?
You got fucking angry, ain't you?
-Yeah, I got angry…
-It's in your head, mate!
Tommy, I know this bastard deserves it!
It's in your fucking head, mate!
I know this bastard deserves it!
I fucking know!
But if you kill him now,
the truce with the London outfits
will be blown to fucking pieces,
-all right?
-Michael.
Don't worry about that truce, kid, right,
'cause it fell apart.
You got nothing to worry about
when it comes to the old
scary London boys.
Which fucking side are you on, Alfie?
I do not give a fuck
right now, kid, right?
I do not want him to spare me
because of some fucking peace pact!
I want him to acknowledge
that his anger is un-fucking-justified!
that he who fights by the sword,
he fucking dies by it, Tommy.
So, what, they took your boy,
did they, eh?
They got your boy?
And what fucking line
am I supposed to have crossed?
How many fathers, right,
how many sons, yeah,
have you cut, killed, murdered,
fucking butchered, innocent and guilty,
to send straight to fucking hell,
ain't ya?
Just like me!
You fucking stand there,
you judging me,
stand there and talk to me
about crossing some fucking line.
If you pull that trigger, right,
you pull that trigger
for a fucking honorable reason.
Like an honorable man,
not like some fucking civilian
that does not understand
the wicked way of our world, mate.
Look, Tommy, the killing of Alfie Solomons
is not going to help.
It'll be very bad for business.
Michael…
go and call Inspector Moss.
Tell him it's Palmer.
Well said, Alfie.
Well said.
[groans]
I did not know about your boy, though.
I know.
I saw.
[Ruben] Hello?
[gun cocks]
Good Lord.
Polly.
Why didn't you come?
I was going to get on the train last night
but then I…
I realized I simply wasn't ready
to enter your world.
Good God. I'm shaking.
Good.
Right now, I'm ready.
I have been searching all night for you.
Polly, whatever you've been told,
it's not true.
[breathing heavily]
The painting was wrong.
She was too sure of herself.
I'm not.
Not anymore.
I can paint another.
[sobbing and sniffling]
Polly.
What the fuck am I doing?
I want a dull life. I want you.
I want you. I want you.
I want you to paint me
in a dress that I bought in a shop.
We have a life?
I think so.
[telephone ringing]
Hello?
[receiver dings]
I demand to see my solicitor!
I have my right to have him here!
Gilbert Palmer, I want to talk to you
about a missing kid.
[grunting]
We are Peaky Blinders.
Where is he?
-Deep breath.
-[muffled breathing]
Where is he?
[birds cawing]
[car approaching]
[shouting indistinctly]
What the fuck
are you doing here, Tommy?
They've taken my boy, Johnny.
Everything's fucking changed.
I have to get the hole dug
before midnight.
Do you hear me?
Are you not going after Charles yourself?
Tommy!
[Michael] I was, uh…
This morning
I was out on the road with Tommy.
I killed a man.
He needed cover. I was all he had.
What did he give you?
He said it's good for close range.
You're better with my gun.
No, no, this is mine now.
Feels part of me hand.
Where'd you hit him?
I hit him in the side of the head.
How was you when he went down?
Tommy said I did all right.
This is where we think
Charles is being held.
They're not expecting nobody,
so you should be alone.
There's two good men there.
You do what they say.
But I fire the bullet. All right?
Yes, you can be there.
But it's better if I do it.
See, these are experienced men, Michael.
When you're sure the kid's safe,
you call Finn.
All right.
Come on, boys.
[door closing]
[Hughes] Ah, hello, there.
Here you go. How's that?
You like a spoon? A shiny spoon?
Do you want to hold the spoon there?
[grunting]
[indistinct chatter]
[man] All out, boys!
Wild cat strike!
[indistinct yelling]
This locomotive…
couples in 15 minutes.
If we do not hear word by 10:00…
[sniffs]
we blow it up.
There's men on board, Arthur.
Yeah.
Six men on board, Charlie.
Driver,
stoker,
and four men I handpicked myself.
Me and John picked those men.
It is me and John
who will pull the switch.
The rest of you men can go home.
[train whistle blowing]
[William] Tommy. Tommy.
-He's got the shakes. Help me with him.
-[Tommy grunts]
Get him out. Get him out!
Bringing him through.
We need to move. Now!
[steam whooshing]
[train screeches]
[engine stops]
You wait here.
I will do the killing.
That's a fucking order.
[grunts]
You move too fast, Thomas.
[rumbling]
-We need more timber.
-Then make it safe.
-I'll go on.
-Thomas, it's too fucking wet.
-It's sludge.
-Make it fucking safe!
-And I'll go on!
-[sighs]
Okay.
[breathing heavily]
[panting]
[blows air]
[baby whimpering]
[gun cocks]
[panting]
What do you think you're doing, boy?
Please don't.
-Please don't shoot. Please don't shoot.
-[baby whimpers]
Please don't. Please.
[grunts]
-You fucking rat.
-[Michael groans]
-What do you think you're doing?
-[grunting]
You know who you're fucking messing with?
[groaning and choking]
[train whistling]
We don't have much time.
I'm gonna take your fucking life from you.
Let's go!
[Tommy grunts]
You're a gypsy bastard.
-[grunts]
-[screams]
[train honking]
Who wants to be in heaven, eh?
[train chugging]
Who wants to be in heaven when you can be
sending men to fucking hell. [chuckles]
Hey.
I'll do it, Arthur, eh. I'll do it.
Get up!
-I'll take him!
-No!
This bastard's mine.
Go call Finn.
I told Tommy I'll do it.
So, I'll do it.
[Hughes grunts]
[Michael panting]
[telephone ringing]
Arthur, wait!
Charlie's safe.
[exploding]
[Finn] Fuck!
[train wreck clattering and shattering]
[grunts]
[panting]
[chuckles]
-It's all right.
-[baby coos]
[baby crying]
Oh…
[baby continues crying]
[whirring]
Let me speak to him.
-Hello, Charlie.
-[baby mumbling]
Hello, Charlie.
Can you hear me?
Yeah.
Yeah, you go to bed.
Good boy.
[sobbing]
Where the hell have you been?
I've been out in Maypole.
There's been some trouble.
I can't stay.
You can't stay?
Tommy needs my help.
It's family business.
No. No. Please.
I'm sorry.
Please.
[breathing heavily]
Where is he?
[Ada] He's upstairs.
Mr. Shelby, this is Monsieur Silk.
He is here on behalf
of the Parisian buyers.
He needs to verify the value.
It was a pleasure doing business with you
these past few months.
You would never steal from your family,
would you? [chuckles]
The collection
was mostly my mother's anyway.
It was more mine than theirs.
And they would never have sold it.
They would have wasted it on a lost cause.
You needed a tunnel.
I need your signature
to make this sale legal.
[Silk] Confirmed, the original
Duke Alexander Petrovich's collection.
To raise a legal bill of sale
and get this across the border,
I need authorization signed by yourself
in the family name, in my presence.
As we agreed,
half for the tunnel,
half for the signature.
Where will you go?
Vienna.
-There is a man waiting for me.
-[Tommy chuckles]
Poor man.
You?
Birmingham.
I'm going to buy a racehorse,
have it trained.
Also, £5,000 for the sex.
And £5,000 for helping you
through the grief of losing your wife.
You didn't even come close.
[Silk clears throat]
The papers are in order.
Now, I just need your signature
for the provenance.
Of course. I have a pen.
At home, these jewels saw way worse.
That's why they are all cursed.
As are we, Mr. Shelby.
If you're ever in Vienna, look me up.
[door opens and closes]
Before I begin,
I want to let you know
I made a mistake.
I made a mistake
and I want to apologize to all of you.
Arthur,
you warned me against getting involved
in Russian business.
And you were right.
Mmm.
I doubted your wife.
For that I'm sorry.
Linda, I have added £3,000 here
in the hope that you'll forgive me.
Apology accepted.
Esme, I doubted you as well.
Now John's got innocent lives
on his conscience.
-Ordinary working men--
-Yeah, all right, Esme. Got it.
No, she's right.
You and Arthur
are gonna have to share that burden.
But I hope
the house that you can buy with this
can become a place of contemplation.
Perhaps redemption.
Charlie, for lost tools, dangerous goods
and Curly's wise words.
Johnny, for board and lodgings.
Lizzie.
Michael,
for the killings.
£5,000 each for the cutting
and the shooting.
-No, Tommy…
-What?
Tell me, eh!
This is who I am!
And this is all I can give you
for what you given me.
Your hearts and your souls.
Yesterday I nearly lost my son.
You should fucking understand that.
For what, eh?
For what? For this? For this? [chuckles]
And I know you all want me to say
that I'll change.
That this fucking business will change.
But I've learnt something
in the last few days.
Those bastards, those bastards
are worse than us!
Politicians, fucking Judges,
Lords and Ladies.
They are worse than us.
And they will never admit us
to their palaces
no matter how legitimate we become.
Because of who we are.
Because of who we fucking are,
because of where we're fucking from.
Isn't that right, Ada?
Our Ada knows.
She got smart about the revolution.
And she knows you have to get
what you want your own way.
Lizzie, I want it known
that money was for you
because some nights it was you
who stopped my heart from breaking.
No one else.
And the rest of you,
you took the King's shilling.
You took the King's fucking shilling.
When you take the King's shilling,
the King expects you to kill.
Right, Arthur?
Yeah.
That's how it works. Right, John?
That's right.
That's right, Pol.
That's fucking right.
Tommy,
you've had a bad time.
We understand.
So at an alternative time,
when we have all recovered,
I would like to put before the family
an alternative view
of the future
of the Shelby Company Limited.
A more hopeful view.
[baby crying]
Which I, for one,
would quite like to hear.
As would I.
[Linda] Come on, Arthur.
The train for the dock leaves in one hour.
Then we get the boat to New York
and it'll all be in the past.
I'll be off then, Tom.
[Arthur sniffles]
I'll see you, eh?
I'll see you, brother.
Bye, Curly.
You can go, but you won't get far, Arthur.
Uh…
All right, Tom.
I spoke to Moss last night.
He told me
that the Chief Constable of Birmingham
has issued a warrant for your arrest.
Murder, sedition,
conspiracy to cause explosion.
John, they're coming for you as well.
Murder, conspiracy to cause explosion.
-Michael…
-[Arthur] What the fuck?
…for the murder of Hughes.
Polly…
Wait a minute.
What the fuck are you talking…
…the murder
of Chief Inspector Chester Campbell.
[clamoring]
The people that we betrayed last night,
they want to bring us down.
-They control the police…
-[knock on door]
…they control the judges,
they control the juries,
they control the jails.
But they do not control
the elected government.
-Listen to me!
-Why didn't you tell us before?
-You are my brother!
-Listen to me.
So I've made a deal…
-They'll hang us!
-…in return for giving evidence
-against them.
-[Arthur] We'll fucking hang.
It's all taken care of.
Lizzie, collect up the money
and bring it to the cellar.
You will all get your money in due course.
When the police get in, do not resist.
You go with them,
you do not say anything.
Arthur, I've made a deal with people
even more powerful than our enemies.
-[Linda] Arthur!
-Trust me.
[indistinct screaming and clamoring]
Trust me.
You did this deliberately!
You made this happen to keep us!
-Come here. Come here.
-[Linda screaming]
Come on now. We have to run.
[indistinct yelling and screaming]
[Arthur] Fuck you!
[indistinct screaming and yelling]
[theme song playing]